<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AMIT PHADKE</title>
    <link>https://amitp13.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AMIT PHADKE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amitp13.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy of a song</title>
      <link>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/spotify_eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/spotify_eda/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing Billboard Hot 100 from 1960 to 2020 Introduction From the first week of December to the final week of November, Billboard runs a year-end chart giving us the highest performing songs for a given year. The year-end charts are calculated by a very straightforward cumulative total of yearlong sales, streaming, and airplay points which gives a more accurate picture of any given year&amp;rsquo;s most popular tracks. Thanks to Spotify&amp;rsquo;s API we can get data for these all these songs and analyze them to get a clear picture of an anatomy of a popular song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income analysis of adults in the USA</title>
      <link>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/income_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/income_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following jupyter notebook is an analysis into the Database for Adult Income in the United States. The Us Adult income dataset was extracted by Barry Becker from the 1994 US Census Database. The data set consists of anonymous information such as occupation, age, native country, race, capital gain, capital loss, education, work class and more. Each row is labelled as either having a salary greater than &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;50K&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;&amp;lt;=50K&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moneyballing T20 Cricket</title>
      <link>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/moneyball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/moneyball/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In 2002 Oakland Athletics&#39; general manager Billy Beane and executive Paul DePodesta changed the game of baseball. They achieved this by using math and statistics. They built a team with fairly low valued players. However, These players had high stats that pointed towards more wins. Many doubted their model, but by the end of the season the Oakland Athletics went on to win a 103 games that season and won 20 consecutive games breaking the famous New York Yankees record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song Recomendation System using Spotify Data</title>
      <link>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/song-recomender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/song-recomender/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This workbook deep dives into the spotify data and demonstrates a recommendation system based on a songs’s audio properties. With the help of Spotify’s API we can get a songs’s energy, loudness, dancebility, amount of instrumentallness and valence. These properties possibly are related to each other and can be clustered to get similar songs. The aim of the project will be to use clustering algorithms to build a recommendation system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tableau Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitp13.github.io/projects/tab/</guid>
      <description>1. UFC Analysis After my analysis in UFC. I want to dive deeper with my analysisand gain more insights on the data. This story is a collection of dashboard that looks at UFC bouts and the athletes participating in the event.
Tableau Link: https://public.tableau.com/views/UFC_15952798007950/Story1?:language=en&amp;amp;:embed_code_version=3&amp;amp;:loadOrderID=0&amp;amp;:display_count=y&amp;amp;:origin=viz_share_link
 var divElement = document.getElementById(&#39;viz1604298825219&#39;); var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName(&#39;object&#39;)[0]; vizElement.style.width=&#39;1016px&#39;;vizElement.style.height=&#39;991px&#39;; var scriptElement = document.createElement(&#39;script&#39;); scriptElement.src = &#39;https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js&#39;; vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement); 2. India in the Olympics I have deep dived into the Olympics in this dashboard, specifically The Indian Olympics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
